<xml xmlns="https://developers.google.com/blockly/xml">
<description>
<![CDATA[

## Sensor Description

The VL53L0X is a new generation Time-of-Flight (ToF) laser-ranging module housed in a small package , providing accurate distance measurement 
over a wide range of target reflectances. It can measure absolute distances up to 2m, and has several potential applications in mechanics experiments.

It integrates a leading-edge SPAD array (Single Photon Avalanche Diodes) and embeds ST’s second generation FlightSense™ patented technology.
The VL53L0X’s 940 nm VCSEL emitter (Vertical Cavity Surface-Emitting Laser), is totally invisible to the human eye, 
coupled with internal physical infrared filters, and this enables longer ranging distance, higher immunity to ambient light, and better robustness to cover glass optical crosstalk. 

## This Sensor can be used to design several experiments to do with classical mechanics.

The SR04 sound based ranging module suffers from limitations such as not being able to reflect effectively from spherical surfaces . 
For most pendulums, the bob is spherical. The VL53L0X only needs the surface to be slightly reflective to light, and is a better alternative.


## The Mass and Spring problem

When a mass suspended on a spring is made to oscillate, the period of oscillation is given by T = 2 * pi * sqrt( m/k), 
where m is the mass and k is the spring constant. We can measure the period of oscillation by measuring the distance 
to the moving mass as a function of time. The distance versus time graph is fitted with a sine function to calculate the frequency.


## Online Resources

+ [Blog Post](https://csparkresearch.in/seel3/android/add-vl53l0x-add-sensor-android-app.html)

]]>
</description>


      <block type="text_print" id="XaxAGz^/lws6NcFR_N`A" x="50" y="104">
        <value name="TEXT">
          <shadow type="text" id="OPN,P7Iuh%t/onC[s[4A">
            <field name="TEXT">abc</field>
          </shadow>
          <block type="text_join" id="q*9r|H4f0,xSmw~(c6nH">
            <mutation items="3"></mutation>
            <value name="ADD0">
              <block type="text" id="OGPnjS~Z/+stDrbVeGE)">
                <field name="TEXT">VL53L0X measured distance : </field>
              </block>
            </value>
            <value name="ADD1">
              <block type="read_VL53L0X" id="2:Xp|IPsc+ek7x-^zlCG">
                <field name="CHANNEL">0</field>
              </block>
            </value>
            <value name="ADD2">
              <block type="text" id="D)vX]|45]DsU7}+|S8~4">
                <field name="TEXT"> mm</field>
              </block>
            </value>
          </block>
        </value>
      </block>
    </xml>
