<xml xmlns="https://developers.google.com/blockly/xml">
<description>
<![CDATA[


## The capture1 function

This function instructs the hardware to record a set of  voltage values with a predefined time gap (micro seconds) between each reading.

We then plot the data returned by this function which is of the form `[X[], Y[]]` where X is a set of time values in mS units, and Y is the set of voltages read for each.


The above 2 steps are repeated 50 times, giving you a functional oscilloscope interface

### Exercise

+ Connect the WG sine wave output to the A1 input and run the oscilloscope 
+ Find out why the measured sine wave plot is not stationary but keeps jumping around with a different starting phase each time.
+ Drag the `trigger` block and attach it above the repeat loop and redo the above. 

## Main Oscilloscope Utility

GO to the home screen and open the oscilloscope for full functionality.

- Channel Selection
   The four channels A1, A2, A3 and MIC can be selected for display using the Check buttons on the left side .

- Input Voltage Range
   Pulldown menus are provided against each channel for selecting the input voltage range. A1 and A2 have a maximum range of +/- 16 V

- Amplitude and Frequency    
   The ANALYSIS checkbutton fits the input signals against a standard Sine wave equation, and show frequency and amplitude. For more than one channel, the phase different W.r.t. the first trace is also shown
   
- Time base Slider
   The time base slider is for selecting the duration of the X-axis. The allowed full range can be set from 1mS to 5 Sec
   
- Trigger Controls
   A digital storage oscilloscope digitizes periodically and captures the input for a given duration and displays the result. To get a stable trace, the amplitude and slope of the input and the beginning of each capture operation should be kept same. This starting value is decided by the trigger level setting.


]]>
</description>

      <block type="controls_repeat_ext" id="%f/NMFtZ(tQg(:i`%,w:" x="-12" y="-119">
        <value name="TIMES">
          <shadow type="math_number" id="v]Jc+G5WG|e.CWD1@dRg">
            <field name="NUM">50</field>
          </shadow>
        </value>
        <statement name="DO">
          <block type="plot_xyarray" id=":TN3K2f#20JSHp~_]u^1">
            <value name="VALUE">
              <block type="capture1" id="r.fF{`k,E}*8p@)G_$h3">
                <field name="CHANNEL">A1</field>
                <field name="SAMPLES">500</field>
                <field name="TIMEGAP">1</field>
              </block>
            </value>
          </block>
        </statement>
      </block>
    </xml>
